<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Lezamas Treasure</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Maps Activity</string>

    <string name="agricolaText">The Agricultural and Livestock Cooperative of Lezama was established in 1925, formed by eighteen villagers of the town. At that time, a better defense of their activities in the agricultural and livestock sector began to be organized, gaining great importance among the inhabitants of Lezama and its rural surroundings.</string>
    <string name="txakoli">With an extension of 9 hectares, it is located in the Bilbo Handia region, in the heart of Txorierri, and, of course, in Lezama. The climate is mesothermal, with mild temperatures and rainfall. The soils are loamy-clayey, planted mainly with local vine varieties "Hondarrabi Zuri" and "Hondarrabi Zuri Zerratia," as well as other minor varieties such as "Petit Manseng" and "Riesling" facing south.</string>
    <string name="udala">Come and enjoy the Txorierri valley in Lezama! Visit the website of the Txorierri Consortium to discover all the options: routes, restaurants, accommodations, transportation, etc. www.txorierri.eus</string>
    <string name="harategia">We are in the Lezama butcher shop, where a very popular product in the town and its surroundings is elaborated. Finding that product may take some work, but you will have some useful photos to help you.</string>
    <string name="santamaria">We are currently at the Church of Santa María, located in the center of Lezama. The Church of Santa María was built in the 16th century and has a Gothic style.</string>
    <string name="dorrea">We have arrived in the Aretxalde neighborhood, and we have the Lezama tower in front of us. This tower was once a fortified military site. Additionally, it was a symbol of economic and social power, indicating the noble origin of its owners.</string>
    <string name="arkua">The "San Mamés" soccer field was built in 1913 and has undergone several expansions since then. In 1945, it was expanded, and a large iron arch was installed on the west stand. This arch became one of the distinctive features of the soccer field and the club itself. San Mamés field was demolished in 2013, but after some popular mobilizations, it was decided to preserve the arch. So they dismantled the arch, restored it, and moved it to the facilities that Athletic has in Lezama.</string>

    <!-- General -->
    <string name="homeButton">Exit</string>
    <string name="btnValidate">Validate</string>
    <string name="btnBack">Back</string>
    <string name="btnContinue">Continue</string>
    <string name="btnRepeat">Repeat</string>
    <string name="btnDarkMode">Dark mode</string>

    <!-- Admin Login -->
    <string name="adminloginTitle">Hello</string>
    <string name="adminloginSubtitle">Enter the password</string>
    <string name="adminloginPassword">Password</string>
    <string name="incorrecto">Incorrect password</string>

    <!-- Main Menu -->
    <string name="mainMenuTitulo1">The Mystery of Lezama</string>
    <string name="mainMenuTitulo2">Lezama</string>
    <string name="mainMenuAjustes">Settings</string>
    <string name="mainMenuJugar">Play</string>
    <string name="mainMenuModoLibre">Free Mode</string>

    <!-- Differences -->
    <string name="diferenciasTitulo">Find 6 differences</string>
    <string name="diferenciasRestantes">Remaining differences:</string>

    <!-- INFO -->
    <string name="terminar">FINISH</string>
    <string name="title_activity_puzzle">Puzzle Activity</string>
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <!-- SETTINGS -->
    <string name="profesor">Teacher Mode</string>
    <string name="inicio">Home</string>
    <string name="eliminar">Delete</string>
    <string name="nuevo">New</string>
    <string name="partida">Game</string>
    <string name="error_ajustes_1">You can´t delete all the games</string>

    <!-- Multiple choice -->
    <string name="multipleChoiceExplain">Choose the correct answer</string>
    <string name="multipleChoiceAnswer">Answer</string>

    <string name="zureerantzuna">Your answer</string>

    <!-- Insert words -->
    <string name="insertWordsExplain">Complete the text</string>

    <!-- Crossword -->
    <string name="wordSearchExplain">Find the following words</string>
    <string name="mensaje_fallido">You failed!</string>

    <!-- Repeat -->
    <string name="terminar_juego">Game over</string>

    <!-- Multiple Choice -->
    <!-- 1.3 -->
    <string name="galdera1.3">Which one is the ox?</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.3">b</string>

    <!-- 1.4 -->
    <!--1-->
    <string name="galdera1.4.1">In which moments of the year are the ox tests carried out?</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.1.a">During rural festivals</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.1.b">At Christmas</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.1.c">During Holy Week</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.4.1">a</string>

    <!--2-->
    <string name="galdera1.4.2">How much do the oxen weigh?</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.2.a">Between 100 and 200 kg</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.2.b">Between 500 and 650 kg</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.2.c">Between 650 and 750 kg</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.4.2">b</string>

    <!--3-->
    <string name="galdera1.4.3">What do the oxen eat before participating in the tests?</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.3.a">Abas</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.3.b">Lettuce</string>
    <string name="aukera1.4.3.c">Pods</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.4.3">a</string>

    <!-- 4.3 -->
    <!--1-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.1">Who was Mikel Zarate?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.1.a">Basque writer</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.1.b">Enthusiast of Basque poetry</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.1.c">The most famous writer in Spain</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.1.d">Famous bertsolari (improviser)</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.1">a</string>

    <!--2-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.2">When was he born?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.2.a">In the 18th century</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.2.b">In 1935</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.2.c">In the 21st century</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.2.d">In 1933</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.2">d</string>

    <!--3-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.3">Where was he born?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.3.a">In Bilbao</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.3.b">In France, although he was Basque-speaking</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.3.c">In Lezama</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.3.d">In Pamplona</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.3">c</string>

    <!--4-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.4">Where did he study as a student?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.4.a">In the Summer Courses of Derio</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.4.b">In the summer school of Derio</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.4.c">In the Summer Courses of Deusto</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.4.d">In the summer school of Deusto</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.4">a</string>

    <!--5-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.5">How many books did he publish?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.5.a">He did not publish any books</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.5.b">1</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.5.c">2</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.5.d">More than 10, as he was a writer</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.5">b</string>

    <!--6-->
    <string name="galdera4.3.6">When did he publish the book of childrens stories?</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.6.a">In 1973</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.6.b">In 1933</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.6.c">In 1793</string>
    <string name="aukera4.3.6.d">In 1937</string>
    <string name="erantzun4.3.6">a</string>

    <!-- Pistak -->
    <!-- 1.1-->
    <string name="galdera1.1">What sport was practiced here?</string>
    <string name="pista1.1">Clue: Find the relation between the sound and the pictures</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.1a">DRAG TESTS</string>
    <string name="erantzun1.1b">DRAG TESTS</string>

    <!-- 2.1 -->
    <string name="galdera2.1">In the Lezama butcher shop, they prepare a very popular product with these ingredients. What product is it?</string>
    <string name="erantzun2.1a">CHORIZO</string>
    <string name="erantzun2.1b">CHORIZOS</string>

    <!-- 3.1 -->
    <string name="galdera3.1">Do you know what drink this is?</string>
    <string name="erantzun3.1a">TXAKOLI</string>
    <string name="erantzun3.1b">WHITE WINE</string>

    <!-- 5.2 -->
    <string name="galdera5.2">What do you see in the church? What representative objects does it have? Discuss among yourselves.</string>
    <string name="erantzun5.2a">BELLS</string>
    <string name="erantzun5.2b">BELL</string>

    <!-- Titulos fragments-->
    <string name="pistakTitle">With these clues, answer the question</string>
    <string name="crucigramaTitle">Fill in the blanks following the definitions</string>
    <string name="sopaLetrasTitle">Find the following words</string>
    <string name="multipleChoiceTitle">Choose the correct answer</string>
    <string name="puzleTitle">Complete the puzzle</string>
    <string name="infoTitle">Information</string>
    <string name="insertWordsTitle">Choose the correct words</string>
    <string name="juegoTorreTitle">Place items correctly</string>
    <string name="mapTitle">Get to know Lezama</string>
    <string name="ordenarImagenesTitle">Place the pictures</string>
    <string name="puzzleTitle">Puzzle</string>
    <string name="videoTitle">Watch the video</string>

    <!-- Repetir -->
    <string name="continuar">Do you want to continue the game?</string>
    <string name="si">Continue</string>
    <string name="no">Repeat</string>

    <!-- Info -->
    <string name="Juego1_2">In this place, we are next to the Lezama agricultural cooperative. There, the annual bull tests are held. In the case of Lezama, these tests are carried out during the festivities. Usually, the bulls weigh between 500 and 650 kg. On the days leading up to the most important tests or bets, the bulls work is reduced, and a special diet regime is established; the basis of this regime is turnips.</string>
    <string name="Juego2_2">The best blood sausages in Biscay are found in Lezama, having already won awards. Blood sausages are made with pig blood, onions, leeks, chard, pork belly, rice, red pepper, and salt. In addition, during the towns festivals, a blood sausage dinner is held as a tradition among the locals. The making of blood sausages is left for the first days of May and are a significant part of Lezamas festivities.</string>
    <string name="Juego2_4">...</string>
    <string name="Juego3_2">The drink shown in the picture is Txakoli. Txakoli is a white wine produced mainly in the Basque Country, starting from the Courbu variety of grapes. Txakoli, especially, is produced in the Basque Country.</string>
    <string name="Juego3_3">Now we are in one of the most famous wineries in Spain, "Lezamako Magalarte Txakolina." This winery is a family business with a great tradition in apple growing and cider production. They make Txakoli based on traditional techniques and with the help of current technologies.</string>
    <string name="Juego3_5">...</string>
    <string name="Juego4_1">Mikel Zarate Lejarraga was born in Lezama in 1933. He was a writer, specifically a Basque writer. From the beginning of the 1970s, he worked as a teacher at the Derio Summer Courses and also at the Bilbao Language School. In 1976, the La Gran Enciclopedia Vasca publishing house published his doctoral thesis: "Influencias del vascuence en la lengua castellana" (Influences of Basque on the Spanish language). In the field of literature, Lezamakoak wrote both prose and poetry. He published only one novel: "Haurgintza minetan" (1973) and left another unfinished.</string>
    <string name="Juego4_4">...</string>
    <string name="Juego5_1">"Now we are at Santa Maria Church, located in the heart of Lezama. Santa Maria Church was built in the 16th century and has a Gothic style."</string>
    <string name="Juego5_3">As you may know, the church bells indicate the hours, from 8 in the morning to 9 at night. It rings continuously, and the number of strikes depends on the hour, that is, if it is 8 oclock, 8 strikes will be heard, and at 9, 9 strikes... this continues until noon, where 12 strikes are reached. From that point onwards, it starts again from zero, that is, one strike in an hour and not 13. The bells also ring to announce the death of someone. If the deceased is a man, 3 strikes are made, followed by another phase of 3 strikes, and finally, to conclude, 3 strikes again. If the deceased is a woman, the first 2 strikes, then another phase, and to conclude, 3 strikes as well.</string>
    <string name="Juego5_6">...</string>
    <string name="Juego6_1">"San Mamés" football field was built in 1913 and has been expanded several times since then. In 1945, the field was enlarged, and for this reason, a large iron arch was installed in the western stand. This turned it into one of the distinctive features of the football field and the club itself.</string>
    <string name="Juego6.3">...</string>
    <string name="Juego7_1">We have arrived at the Aretxalde neighborhood, and in front of us is the Lezama Tower. (Photo of Lezama Tower)</string>
    <string name="HASIERAKO_JARDUERA_1">Who are you? I have never seen you around here... Hello, I am Lamia, and I have been living in the surroundings of Lezama with other lamias, especially in the rivers, for a long time. I have always been here, so I know the whole history of Lezama better than anyone else. Wait a moment, how about an idea I have had for a while! Have you ever come to know the cultural and historical heritage of Lezama? (short pause) Well, I will be your guide on this exciting adventure. I am delighted to share with you the most significant places of Lezama, such as the Lezama agricultural cooperative, the local butcher shop, the "Lezamako Magalarte Txakolina" winery, the town hall, Santa Maria Church, the facilities of Athletic Club, and the Lezama Tower. In addition, I have thought of various activities to do in those places.Are you ready? If so, lets go to discover Lezama!</string>
    <string name="AMAIERAKO_JARDUERA_1">We have reached the end of our journey. We have given many laps around the town, learning about significant places and important people, immersing ourselves in their local customs. I can say with great satisfaction that you have fully experienced the cultural and historical heritage of Lezama, and thanks to knowing this, you will help preserve its heritage for the future, just as I do.\nSurely, you will be a little tired, but before leaving Lezama, I have a final surprise for you. I am sure that you have paid attention throughout the journey, so it will be easy. You will need to fill in a map by indicating the route you have taken, thus always remembering those important points you have visited.</string>
    <string name="AMAIERAKO_JARDUERA_3">The moment to say goodbye to the traveler has arrived. With the visit from top to bottom, you have learned a lot about the town. You have discovered its customs, people, and places, and you will forever have the experience of it. Now Lezama is a part of you.\nYou may be a little sad, but before leaving, I have a small gift for you as a memento of the entire journey. Rest assured, you have done well throughout the journey, so it will be easy. You will need to fill in a map by indicating the route you have taken, thus always remembering those important points you have visited.</string>


</resources>

